Ifeoluwa Akinremi-Wade

Chicago, Illinois 60641 | 760-617-3180 | ifeoluwa.akinremi.wade@gmail.com | Github | Blog | LinkedIn

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with a background in React. Passionate about finding creative solutions to complex problems and my love for Jazz inspires me to think outside the box. With more than 10 years of working collaboratively with peers, including those in lead roles and client-facing roles, I am confident in my ability to make valuable contributions to any technical team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Tech skills: Ruby, HTML, CSS, Rails, Javascript, React, Redux

Current courses: Udemy: The Modern React Bootcamp (Hooks, Context, NextJS, Router), W3schools: Java

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

Database Driven React Application for Daycare Github | Demo

A React application that maintains a database for a daycare and enrolled children.

- Utilized javascript fetch, async actions, redux-thunk, and Rails API database for data persistence
- Sustained Redux global state storage and modification with Redux middleware
- Employed react-router and proper RESTful routing for client-side navigation
- Designed client-side with CSS for user experience

Database Driven Javascript Productivity SPA - Github | Demo

Javascript single page application that creates and manages project tasks

- Generated Rails API using SQL, Active Record, and CRUD
- Translated JSON responses into JavaScript model objects utilizing ES6 syntax
- Manipulated the DOM using event handlers and iterators
- Designed client-side with CSS for user experience

Full-Stack Ruby on Rails Health-Based Application - Github | Demo

Ruby on Rails Health-based web application that connects black doctors of various specialties to black patients

- Constructed with Rails MVC and Active Record
- Created RESTful API schema using SQL
- Implemented full CRUD functionality in controllers for multiple models
- Utilized Google oauth for user authentication

EXPERIENCE

Chingu Chicago, Illinois 03/2022 - 04/2022

Software Engineer, Cohort

- Accelerated team production via Agile methodologies and JIRA, meeting 6-week deadline.
- Developed and maintained Ruby on Rails server and postgresSQL DB for full CRUD functionality.
- Collaborated on JSON Web Tokens authentication for client-server security.

LensCrafters Chicago, Illinois Eyecare Advisor 09/2017 - 06/2018

- Enhanced Optomap imaging and sales by 80% through patient communication; received bonus.
- Boosted POS database productivity by consulting optician, optometrist, and management.

California Baptist University

Student Disabilities Office student success assistant

Riverside, California 01/2015 - 11/2016

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Chicago, Illinois Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and Javascript Program 11/2021

California Baptist University

Bachelor of Arts, Psychology

Riverside, California 05/2017